The AI space never seems to rest and the
pace of innovation is only getting
wilder. Just yesterday, we saw the
launch of Claude 4.5 Sonnet, a frontier
coding model, followed by glimpses of
Gemini 3.0 coming out next week. And
today, OpenAI just dropped Sora 2, its
nextG video generation model. But
perhaps the most exciting news for the
open source community is the comeback of
ZAI's new release of the GLM 4.6. A
major upgrade from the already
impressive GLM 4.5 launched just a month
ago. GLM 4.6 6 is designed with a strong
focus for advanced agentic workflows
reasoning as well as realworld coding
capabilities putting it in the direct
competition of large players in the
space like claude as well as open AI.
Now the model pushes boundaries with
support of 200k context exceptionally
well in its performance on software
development tasks and strong reasoning
and search capabilities. But the thing
that makes GLM 4.6 six superior is its
coding performance as an open-source
model that does really well on realworld
tasks. But not just that, the pricing
structure also makes this probably the
best model to go to for software
development tasks due to its efficiency
and quality. But the GLM 4.6 is priced
at 6 cents per 1 million input tokens.
And with cashed input, it's listed at
11, which is pretty good. Now, the
output is listed at $2.20 20 cents per 1
million output tokens and it has a 200k
context window, which isn't the best,
but it's pretty decent considering its
performance. In regards to the
performance, you can see that the GLM
4.6 was able to do quite well across
reasoning, agents, coding, and other
benchmarks cuz it shows clear gains over
the 4.5, which just released yesterday.
It outperforms open-source baselines
like the new Deepseek version 3.2 2 and
nears Cloud Sonnet 4, but trails Sonnet
4.5 in overall coding. Now, in certain
cases, like in Mac as well as GPQ and
live codebench, it does exceptionally
well up against many of these other
models, but in certain cases like
Swaybench rarified as well as Terminal
Bench and Tsquare, you can see that it's
slightly behind Enthropic's new Claude
Sonic 4.5. Before we get started, I just
want to mention that you should
definitely go ahead and subscribe to the
world of AI newsletter. I'm constantly
posting different newsletters on a
weekly basis. So, this is where you can
easily get up-to-date knowledge about
what is happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. If you're
looking to get started with this model,
it's uploaded on HuggingFace. If you had
the requirements to host it locally, you
can easily access it through the ZAI
chatbot where you can simply just select
the GLM4.6 and use it unlimitedly over
here. Now, you also have the ability to
access it for free using an API through
kilo code. They give out free credits
where you can easily access it through
their AI agent, which is something that
I would highly recommend that you do so.
Now another way is through open router
and this is another provider that you
can use via API. So let's get started
and now test this out. To access Kilo
code you can head over to the extension
store within your IDE whether that's VS
code and you can search up Kilo code and
then you can install it which is a free
extension that you can work with. Now
what we can do is select the new GLM4.6
model and you can see that it's
available here and now we can use it to
test out anything. We're going to first
start off by creating a browserbased OS
from scratch that is a Mac OS style. And
essentially the reason why we're doing
this is because we're trying to see how
well this model is in terms of its
system design and architecture skills.
If it's capable of breaking down the
concept of an OS and making it into
modular components. We're going to see
if it's able to code out these different
components, uh, its front-end designing
framework and how well it is in terms of
reasoning. And there we go. Quite
rapidly, Kilo Code was able to output
this Mac OS styled browserbased OS and
it looks absolutely amazing. Guys, this
is probably the best OS I have saw any
model generate. You have a file manager.
You have the terminal. You even have a
notes tab where you can actually have it
write down different sorts of notes,
bold it, add itallic, and a couple other
features. You also have a calculator.
And this is something that mimics the
brow the Mac OS uh style, which is
absolutely amazing. But all these
components were fully generated in a
single shot. And this is probably the
best browser based OS that I had
generated with any sort of model.
Heading over to the GLM chatbot. This is
where we're going to select the 4.6
model. And then we're going to have it
enable the creation of AI slides. And
now we're going to actually have it
create a slide deck on my channel, World
of AI. I simply just provided the URL as
well as the description of my channel.
and we're going to see what this model
is capable of generating in terms of the
slide deck. So let's see what it
actually does. It has a capability of
using web search and it is something
that does really well with tool usage.
What I really like about this model is
that it thoroughly reasons with
individual subtasks that the agents
develop. Usually what happens is when a
model generates a to-do list or any sort
of plan, it is something that a couple
of agents actually thoroughly analyze.
But in this case, this is where it
reasons with each individual subtask,
which is quite impressive. And in terms
of its code speed, it is pretty
impressive. You can see that it is
working on coding out all the individual
slides right now. There we go. It looks
like it has finished generating our
slide deck on our channel and it was
able to extract all the contents by
scraping the web page of our channel
where I was able to get the contents
like our subscriber list as well as our
total views as well as the videos. Now
we have a slide deck that represents the
content information. So it looks like it
did a great job in generating the
overall format of it. Talks about the
channel overview, content focus, talks
about AI coding agents, and it talks
about a couple other things. So I really
like how it did a great job in scraping
the contents. But overall, I would give
it an 8 out of 10 in terms of its
creativity and thoroughly actually
generating all the contents of a slide
deck. Next up, I'm going to have Kilo
Code work on this task of creating a SAS
landing page. This is essentially a
prompt that I would send in to test how
well the model is in terms of its
front-end UX capabilities, how well it
is in terms of generating all the
components. But one thing I noticed is
that say these files,
you can see that these files are pretty
lengthy. And one thing that I realized
is that it's able to code out all of the
components quite rapidly with quality.
And in terms of its pricing, it is
extremely cheap in comparison to other
models. But looks like it has finished
generating it. So let's actually take a
look at it. So I have just opened it up
and this is the output. This is
absolutely amazing guys. Typically we
would see some typical AI generated SAS
landing page which has similar
components like any other model would
generate. But in this case, this is
something that is abstract and it's
something that's different. It uses a
different color scheme and in terms of
the components, it looks like it did a
great job. Now, you can see that there's
also a couple of other things that
generated different uh components like
experience AI in action. This is
something that's new that you wouldn't
see typically in an AI SAS landing page.
There's a pricing structure that I had
generated, some testimonials, seamless
integrations, Q&A, as well as the bottom
footer. This is something that I would
actually deploy for my website. like the
quality is there and it did it pretty
quickly and with good pricing. And you
can see that Kilo Code is still refining
it. It's still working on improving it,
which is why this is the perfect AI
agent you would want to use. Next up,
we're going to have the model generate
SVG code of a butterfly. And we're
trying to see how proficient it is in
generating the SVG code as well as
seeing if it's able to creatively add
new features and focus on symmetry.
Looks like we have now gotten the
generation for our butterfly. And there
we go. This is a pretty cool looking
butterfly. You have eyes, an antenna, a
body structure that has the wings
attached to it. It looks pretty detailed
in my opinion, and I would give this a
pass. Next up, we're testing it on its
mathematical and reasoning skills where
I'm testing it on this prompt where I'm
saying, "You flipped a fair coin
repeatedly. What's the expected number
of flips until the pattern heads, tails,
heads is appearing for the first time?"
And essentially, this is where it's
going to reason on multiple solutions.
And we're trying to see how well it is
in terms of reasoning, modeling out the
different sorts of outcomes. And we're
trying to see how well it is in terms of
stating the transition logic. And you
can see right away it is working on this
where it states out the different
stochastic reasoning and markov modeling
at the start. It is then working on
different conditions as well as
expectations and it comes up with the
correct answer which is 10. So it would
take 10 different steps to get to the
pattern that we're looking for. And you
can see that it did a pretty quick job
and reasoning to get this answer. Now I
know its coding capabilities are pretty
impressive but in terms of its tool
usage as well as reasoning it is way
superior in that front. And you can see
that with the generations that I'm
showcasing here. This is where it was
able to properly and thoroughly generate
a research on a prompt that sent in. And
it did a great job in searching and
scouring the web for different sources.
And it did a great job in compiling it
and generating the deep research. If you
like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. But that's
basically it, guys, for today's video on
the GLM 4.6. Here's my two cents. This
is a perfect open-source model for
coding. It's costefficient and it's
qualitative. It's not the best in terms
of its context, but overall its coding
performance is pretty impressive. It has
advanced reasoning built within and they
exhibit different sorts of tool usage as
well as integrations that makes it more
powerful than ever before. In my
opinion, I would use this as a
costefficient coding model that you can
use locally if you have the compute or
you can even use it through API cuz it's
pretty cheap. But that's basically it
guys for today's video on the GLM 4.6.
Let me know what you guys think. I'll
leave all these links in the
description. Make sure you go ahead and
subscribe to the second channel. Join
the newsletter, join our private
Discord, follow me on Twitter, and
lastly, make sure you guys subscribe,
turn on the notification bell, like this
video, and please take a look at our
previous videos because there's a lot of
videos that you will truly benefit from.
But with that thought, guys, thank you
guys so much for watching. Have an
amazing day. Spread positivity, and I'll
see you guys fairly shortly. This falls.